# **Abdul-Awwal Adesalu**

St. Cloud, MN 56301 • (320)-310-2286

awwalwork@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/abdul-awwal-adesalu • https://github.com/Abdul-Awwal

#### **SUMMARY:**

Student pursuing a Software Engineering Major and Cybersecurity minor at St. Cloud State University. Proficient in Python, C++, React Native, and experienced with tools like Kali Linux, JIRA, and cloud platforms (Azure, AWS). I have experience in CI/CD for software development using Plastic SCM and GitHub, implementing software security using vulnerability scanning, code sanitization, etc. and project management using agile scrum methodologies. I combine technical expertise with strong leadership, communication, and problem-solving skills.

#### **EDUCATION:**

## Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Minor in Cybersecurity.

**Anticipated May 2024** 

St. Cloud State University (SCSU) - Working approximately 20 hours per week while attending college full time.

#### CompTIA Security+ Certification.

December 2023

Relevant knowledge gained: Access Control, Cryptography, Cyber Forensics, Data Security, Disaster Recovery Planning, Firewall configuration, Malware Identification, Mobile Device Security, Network Security, Security Configuration, Security Policies, Threat Analysis, Threat Detection.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, C++, React native, React, HTML, CSS, SQL(Intermediate),
   NextJS(Intermediate), Bash(Intermediate), C#(Intermediate).
- Infrastructure Security Skills Skills: Kali Linux, OpenVAS, CMD, JIRA, Ubuntu, Azure, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, Vulnerability assessment, Incident Response, Networking Management, Docker.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Member, Collegiate Cyber-Defense Club, Saint Cloud State University

August 2023-Present

- Participating in a nationally recognized competition hosted by Raytheon, this competition tests cybersecurity
  and networking skills of students in real time while demanding the continual operation of mission critical
  components.
- Leading a team of eight people, we successfully secured mission critical components and protected them against
  a rival team of professional ethical hackers using Splunk, Nmap, Wireshark and Palo Alto firewall.

- I am currently working with a team of three to develop features for an educational software using Unity VR development kit.
- I implemented the scrum methodology by having daily standups, mid-sprint, and end of sprint meetings where we talked on monitored progress for the project and prioritized backlog items.
- Led the team by using JIRA product management software to assign tasks and develop product backlog and sprint burndown chart as well as employing other sprint management methods.

## Cryptographic Algorithms, Saint Cloud State University

January 2023-May 2023

- Worked with a team of two to implement popular cryptographic algorithms in python such as Caesar, DES,ECC and RSA on text files containing user input and displayed the resulting encrypted text to them.
- Developed decrypting algorithms for each method as well as brute force algorithms for some.
- Developed an algorithm to track both encryption time and decryption time as well as compared times with other
  algorithms to come up with the most efficient one based on speed, security and accuracy.

#### Photoboom, Saint Cloud State University

**January 2022-June 2022** 

- Worked with a team of four to design a mobile application which emulated a social media platform where you
  can post, like and comment on photos.
- Designed the front end of the application using React Native.
- I implemented the scrum methodology by having daily standups, mid-sprint, and end of sprint meetings where we talked on monitored progress for the project and prioritized backlog items.
- Participated in the development of the backend by creating a PostgreSQL database hosted on a Google Cloud Virtual Machine.

## Gas Station Rewards, Saint Cloud State University

August 2022-November 2022

- Worked with a team of three (3) to design a mobile application emulating a Gas Station rewards system where users can spend points they have earned with transactions on other products being sold on the application.
- Designed the front end of the application using React Native
- I implemented the scrum methodology by having daily standups, mid-sprint, and end of sprint meetings where we talked on monitored progress for the project and prioritized backlog items.

 Participate in the backend development of the application by creating a PostgreSQL database hosted on a Microsoft Azure Virtual machine.

**RELEVANT UNDERGRADUATE CLASSES:** Game Development, Computer science 3, Project Management for Software Engineering, Data Mining for Software Engineering, Software Construction, Software Engineering and Human Computer Interaction, Operating systems and applications, Software Quality, Introduction to Database Systems, Software design, Software Analysis, Software Construction, Security Fundamentals and Laws, Ethical Hacking.

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Resident Assistant Director, Residential Life, Saint Cloud State University August 2022 - January 2024

- Managed a receptionist desk of a student residence hall by independently organizing administrative procedures and utilizing advanced functions of Microsoft Office Excel to establish efficient desk operations and smooth distribution of over one hundred packages daily.
- Provided support and guidance for newer community advisors during incidents.
- Managed a group of eighteen desk assistants and organized schedules whilst making sure operations ran smoothly resulting in an efficient desk system.